Connecticut Soldiers Collection
© 2007 University of Connecticut
Philip and Hazel Greene Correspondence Collection.
1941-1947.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Center.
Greene, Philip and Hazel [Collector].
.25 linear feet.
Twenty-three letters addressed to either Philip and/or Hazel Greene between 1941 and 1947 regarding life during World War II. Included are correspondence with family and friends of Winsted, Connecticut.
MSS20060176
Biography
Philip and Hazel Greene, residents of Winsted, Connecticut, were married in circa 1940. Philip was employed by a local firm while Hazel worked for the town hall. During World War II, Philip was drafted into service and was awarded the Purple Heart. During the same time period Hazel served on the town's rationing board.
Scope and Content
The collection contains twenty-three letters addressed to either Philip and/or Hazel Greene dating from 1941 through 1947 regarding life during World War II. Included are correspondence with family and friends from Winsted, Connecticut. Notable family members include Philip's sister Ruth W. Greene and Hazel's brother, Milt Stetson. This collection contains multiple perspectives on medical and nursing care during the war. Discussion between Philip Greene and his friend Arthur E. Roberts contains personal thoughts on the necessity of the war, as well as information on food rationing. As the collection is only correspondences received by Philip and Hazel Greene, pieces of the conversation are missing. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1943 to 1945.
Arrangement
This arrangement alphabetical by correspondent; multiple letters from the same correspondent are arranged chronologically therein.
Series I: Correspondence ( 1941-1947 ).
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to various aspects of Connecticut history, with a special emphasis on the correspondence of Connecticut veterans. See the Connecticut Soldiers Collection for similar collections. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
Envelopes associated with the letters have been removed from the collection after all significant information was transcribed.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Greene, Philip.; Greene, Hazel.
Places:
Winsted (Conn.)
Subjects:
Document Types:
Correspondence.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was purchased from Zachary R. Jones in February 2006.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, 1941-1947
  - Arthur, George H., 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Clyde, Mildred J., 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Fuhrmann, J. J., 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Greene, Philip, 1947 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Greene, Ruth W., 1941, 1944-1945 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Haringa, Harriet, 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Moore, James H., Jr., 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Roberts, Arthur E., 1943-1944 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Stetson, Milt, 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 9)